

# **HOANG PHAN**

# Senior Product Owner | Product Manager

Thu Duc City, Ho Chi Minh City, VN | phone: +84 32 6562 797 | email: <a href="mailto:hoangpm.work@gmail.com">hoangpm.work@gmail.com</a> | www: hoangphan.blog



#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a Senior Product Owner/ Business Analyst, and Product Manager has more than 5 years of experience in Fintech, Banking and Crypto industries.

I can help company to build the effective product in the right way. Highly adaptive and can work in harmony with a wide variety of professionals in cross-functional / multinational teams.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **Kyros Ventures/Ancient8 Finance**

Senior Product Owner & Product Manager - 03/2022 - now

- Product Owner for Dojo Token, the token launchpad on Solana Chain, re-design the UX of product, plan to develop, scope of works and release plan
- Advise process to develop for Dojo NFT (a NFT Launchpad on Solana Chain), sharing experience and business flow about NFT launchpad to development team.
- Product Manager for Ancient8 User Identity, the SSO for all Ancient8 Products. Features: Login with multichain wallets, Email, Discord, GG Account, Twitter. Also build SDK to integrate A8 UID on the different code base projects.
- Product Onwer for Community Engagement Product that help to engage community members.
- Own development from inception to launch which involves scoping with stakeholders, defining FRD, SRS, Usecase, Business Rules, Backlogs, Roadmap, planning releases
- Conduct Market research, Work with partner to gathering the needs, customers interview to identify areas of improvements and what features should do
- Define the development process in the early stage of Dev team
- Guide other BAs/POs about new processes to apply for a new in-house product, challenges, questions, and analytics which bring to output: Pain of users/customers, solutions, requirements

#### MoonRat Finance

Co-founder / Product Lead - 02/2021 - now

- Responsible for product (UX/UI) design (Homepage, App, SupperApp, ...)
- Logo and 2D designer
- Support users with helpdesk portal.
- Execute the user research, survey, data analytic to improve Dapp User Experience
- Build the user guide that help users to be familiar with crypto and MoonRat Dapp/Defi
- Work with other co-founders to define the scope of works, idea, usecase, requirements to build product
- Perform UAT to ensure that validated deliverables meet functional and design specifications and requirements.

## **PhiEnglish**

Former - Founder - 08/2019 - 02/2022

- Build my own product and business that helps 75 students can speak basic English
- Process of product from testing idea, MVP, to run it well.
- Purpose of product is "Help students speak English better", that why the class is only ~5\$/hour, and bring to me 600\$/month for profit
- Develop the system to mangage teachers, students, courses and classes by myself
- Managed 14 teachers, 2 staffs and 75 students in approximately 2 years

#### **VNPAY**

Business Analyst - 12/2019 - 05/2021

- Give solutions to Banks' digital development team
- Analyst and work with both Bank, VNPAY, 3<sup>rd</sup> teams to develop product (MB, IB, Omni App)
- Build VNPAY's products such as: eKYC, bus booking (Cambodia), billing topup (Myanmar)
- Work with UI/UX designers to give the best app interfaces to Bank and VNPAY's products.
- Help BA's members in VNPAY develop their skills

List of projects:

- Mobile Banking/Omni:
  - Main projects: AB Ditizen (ABBANK), IVB Mobile, SCB Mobile Banking, Kienlongbank Mobile banking, Loyalty (VCB)
  - Support: Vietcombank, HDBank, SaiGon Bank, Eximbank, NamA Bank, Vietjet POS
- Others: Topup/Billing Cambopay, Topup/Billing Myanmar, eKYC (on MB), Bus Booking (full project start from scratch), ...

#### **KYANON**

Business Analyst/Quality Control/Product Release – 08/2018 – 08/2019

- Give solutions to Kyanon's customers to build their app
- Work directly to product director and UX design to build app
- Work with Agile framework in development process, help to build process between development team and stakeholders
- Define Scope of Work, timeline, ....
- Manage and release product on time.
- Get feedback directly from users to analyst and give solutions to fix or enhance product
- Help BA, Tester's members in KYANON develop their skills

MORE (IMT Solutions, Freelancer Developer) – also related to BA, Tester, Product Owner jobs

### **EDUCATION**

Software Engineering – Ho Chi Minh University of Information Technology (UIT), Vietnam

English as Second Language – Colegio San Agustin – LSLC, Philippines.

# SKILLS CAN PROVIDE FOR YOUR COMPANY

- BA Planning & Monitoring
- Elicitation & Collaboration
- Solution Evaluation
- Requirements management
- User stories/specifications
- User Acceptance Testing (UAT)/ Delivery product
- Sketching/Wireframing
- UI/UX Analyst/ Product Design (both Sketch, Wireframe, Mockup, Prototype)
- Manage new team (around 10-15 team members, help them develop skills in PO, BA, Tester)
- Build scope of work (SOW)/Backlogs
- Work with development team (UI/UX Designer, PM, BA, Dev, Tester, BO, Stakeholders)
- Release product plan and timeline, roadmap
- Business Analysis (build document, user guide, product analyst)

- Productive measure/Metrics
- Others...

# **EXPECTED SALARY**

- 4500\$ 5000\$ NET MONTHLY
- 100\$/h